<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Scott E Lundgren</title>
  <subtitle>Finding Flexibility in Software &amp; the Body</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/</id>
  <link href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/"/>
  <link href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-07-31T01:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Girl Develop It Launches</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/girl-develop-it-charlotte-launch/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/girl-develop-it-charlotte-launch/</id>
    <published>2014-07-31T01:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T16:41:17-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My hope is you’ll help me get fired from a job I want. Let me explain. At &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://localhost:4567/blend-conference-lightning-edition/"&gt;BlendConf 2013&lt;/a&gt; Ashe Dryden gave a talk on the challenges of entering the technology field. Those challenges affect disproportionately any one that is not a white, straight, single...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My hope is you’ll help me get fired from a job I want. Let me explain. At &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://localhost:4567/blend-conference-lightning-edition/"&gt;BlendConf 2013&lt;/a&gt; Ashe Dryden gave a talk on the challenges of entering the technology field. Those challenges affect disproportionately any one that is not a white, straight, single male. She ended on a list of action items. One was to increase education and access. Among the organizations she mentioned was Girl Develop It that just started a chapter in Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My attendance of the launch event was pure coincidence. At a networking event one of the founders asked me to come. The response to Girl Develop It Charlotte's formation has been great. It is one the largest technical group meetups in Charlotte with over a 120 members! If you want to stay abreast of their events join &lt;a target="_blank" href="meetup.com/Girl-Develop-It-Charlotte-NC/"&gt;GDI Charlotte's meetup group&lt;/a&gt;; it is free and easy. Or follow &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/GDICharlotte"&gt;GDICharlotte&lt;/a&gt; on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m ahead of myself. What is Girl Develop It? It is an organization to provide affordable classes to women who want to learn software development. They provide both through mentorship and hands on instruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the launch event there was great food, cookies (always a plus!), and a photo booth. Founders Crystal and Steph explained how the group formed out of Charlotte’s User Experience meet up. Their goal is to offer classes that focus on programming skills and knowledge, starting off with the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classes will cost around $10/hr. That’s an incredible value for in person training. A typical class will run 2 hours on a weeknight for 4 weeks so the total cost  would be $80. They recognize women often have the role of caregiver so they are working to provide child care during sessions. Besides core classes there will be workshops of other technical topics to meet the skill levels of the group. If you want to teach, teachers get 50% of fees. For instance, a 4 hour workshop with 10 people would pay $200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One of the points she hit was how important they feel it is that women teach women. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel closed the night talking about her own experiences as a developer. The empowerment of that quote is two-fold. One to prove that women are in the field, but two as an avenue for women in the field to gain experience public speaking. From this mutually enriching environment they hope to create mentoring and networking among members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to my opening statement. I’d love to teach a class I’m calling &lt;em&gt;Your Friend Command Line&lt;/em&gt;. It could give a comfortable and powerful understanding of command line so students have a choice in their workflow. I believe I can make the topic fun and less intimidating. Right now I'm figuring out a curriculum and how long the class might be. Yet, I also understand that I should not be the one to teach it. The best outcome might be I teach it once, you encourage a woman to join &amp;amp; she shares the joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hacking Nan &amp; Byron's Beet Burger</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/hacking-nan-byrons-beet-burger/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/hacking-nan-byrons-beet-burger/</id>
    <published>2014-05-13T01:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T19:45:52-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hacking has had a bad wrap for over 40 years. Yet today Facebook is on Hackerway Way and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://detailedblock.com/2014/04/18/hackathonclt-planned-larger-event-2014/"&gt;Charlotte’s hosted a hackathon for a second year&lt;/a&gt;. While hacking still means rule breaking to some, the phrase means a clever solution too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food hacking is still...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hacking has had a bad wrap for over 40 years. Yet today Facebook is on Hackerway Way and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://detailedblock.com/2014/04/18/hackathonclt-planned-larger-event-2014/"&gt;Charlotte’s hosted a hackathon for a second year&lt;/a&gt;. While hacking still means rule breaking to some, the phrase means a clever solution too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food hacking is still a  favorite activity of mine because when I’m dining out I’m looking to bring flavors into my own kitchen. In November at a charity event Lyft held at &lt;a href="http://5church.com"&gt;5 Church&lt;/a&gt;, I enjoyed the beet burger sliders that were among the buffet. It excited me when that restaurant group opened the casual &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.nanandbyrons.com"&gt;Nan &amp;amp; Bryon&lt;/a&gt;’s with their Beet Burger as a main course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been eating vegetarian dinners and there are only so many times one can enjoy a black bean burger. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://eatmorecowbell.com"&gt;Cowbell&lt;/a&gt;’s Shankar Burger of curry pinto &amp;amp; faro is pretty unique, but still is mash of ingredients and cooked. The problem with that approach it is that it has a certain mouth texture that can be unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The greatness of the beet burger is that it is whole, with a resistance for your teeth with great meaty mouth feel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;htop and Chrome Dev Tools my normal investigative weapons were set aside to unlock Nan &amp;amp; Byron’s beet burger. First I started doing research. Google searching “beet burger recipe” turned up some tasty &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.greenkitchenstories.com/grilled-beet-burgers/"&gt;sounding&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.sproutedkitchen.com/home/2013/3/26/smoky-beet-burgers.html"&gt;looking&lt;/a&gt; options. But they all boiled down to the same “cook beets, shred beets, add a bean, mix, form patties, cook” formula. Unfortunately that wasn’t the mouth feel I was hunting. So I started looking into other ways to cook beets because I’ve never prepared them before. I had no idea what to do to them. Then I found this &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://allrecipes.com/recipe/beet-salad-with-goat-cheese/"&gt;beet salad recipe&lt;/a&gt; and how to make this delicious treat became became clear. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="recipe" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Recipe"&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop="name"&gt;Nan &amp;amp; Byron's Beet Burger&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;small&gt;by &lt;span itemprop="author"&gt;Scott E Lundgren&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p itemprop="description"&gt;
    Nan &amp;amp; Byron's Beet burger is a vegetarian alternative that has great meaty mouth feel!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-4"&gt;
      &lt;img itemprop="image" src="../images/nan-byrons-beet-burger.jpg" class="img-rounded img-responsive" /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-8"&gt;
      &lt;ul class="list-inline text-center"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;PREP TIME&lt;/strong&gt;
          &lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;time itemprop="prepTime" content="PT15M"&gt;15 Min&lt;/time&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;COOK TIME:&lt;/strong&gt;
          &lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;time itemprop="cookTime" content="PT30M"&gt;30 Min&lt;/time&gt;
         &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;TOTAL TIME:&lt;/strong&gt;
          &lt;br /&gt;
          &lt;time itemprop="totalTime" content="PT45M"&gt;45 Min&lt;/time&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-4"&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Yield:  &lt;small&gt;&lt;span itemprop="recipeYield"&gt;4 sandwiches&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Category: &lt;small&gt;&lt;span itemprop="recipeCategory"&gt;Vegetarian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-4"&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Method: &lt;small&gt;&lt;span itemprop="cookingMethod"&gt;Bake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Cuisine: &lt;small&gt;&lt;span itemprop="recipeCuisine"&gt;American&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-8"&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;ul class="list-unstyled"&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;4 beets, medium, scrubbed, peeled, sliced in 1/4” thick discs&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;4 buns, hawaiian or wheat, your preference&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;1/2 small red onion, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;1/2 small avocado, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;1/2 cp panko breading or rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;2 oz goat cheese, plain&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;2 tblsp sunflower oil&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li itemprop="ingredients"&gt;arugula&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;div class="col-sm-12" itemprop="recipeInstructions"&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven, 400 degrees&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;On an aluminum foil sheet, layout the beets&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Baste the beets with 1 tblsp olive or sunflower oil&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After 10 min, flip the beets to the other side&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After 20 min, pull them out of the oven, let cool&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dip beets in panko breading or rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Warm up a pan over medium high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add 1 tblsp olive or sunflower oil to the pan&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fry the beets for 3 minutes on each side&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remove beets to a plate lined with a paper towel to drain&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spread goat cheese on the bottom bun, cover with arugula&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Place 3-4 beets to cover the bottom bun&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Top beets with onion &amp;amp; avocado slices, serve&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Winning Charlotte Startup Weekend</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/winning-charlotte-startup-weekend/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/winning-charlotte-startup-weekend/</id>
    <published>2014-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T19:45:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Below is a repostof written to encourage others to be at &lt;a href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org"&gt;Charlotte Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participating in Charlotte’s Startup Weekend (CSW) may not lead to startup fame, cash or prizes. What spending the weekend at CSW will lead to is an understanding of...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Below is a repostof written to encourage others to be at &lt;a href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org"&gt;Charlotte Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participating in Charlotte’s Startup Weekend (CSW) may not lead to startup fame, cash or prizes. What spending the weekend at CSW will lead to is an understanding of getting an idea from nothing to something, meeting some incredibly talented people, and potentially discovering talents you didn’t know you had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed the first two CSWs and signed up in Fall 2011. My teammates &amp;amp; I on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2011/11/06/cribsheet-baby-mood-tracking-with-a-sense-of-humor-charlotte-startup-weekend/"&gt;Cribsheet&lt;/a&gt; won and did &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2011/11/30/cribsheet-receives-global-recognition/"&gt;gain some notoriety&lt;/a&gt;. The following Spring 2012 the team I was on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2012/05/06/meet-the-teams-my-autopilot/"&gt;My Autopilot&lt;/a&gt; didn’t win, but it was an inaugural member of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://revtechlabs.com/"&gt;RevTech Labs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://detailedblock.com/2012/07/14/autopilot-receives-angel-investment/"&gt;received a cash investment&lt;/a&gt;. So for Spring 2013 I wrote the following advice to prep &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://honeystuck.com/"&gt;Katie Levans&lt;/a&gt; whose &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://plateshare.org/"&gt;PlateShare&lt;/a&gt; idea didn’t win either but was accepted into RevTech’s 2.0 class and did recently &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://detailedblock.com/2013/12/12/katie-levans-gives-advice-entrepreneurs/"&gt;win prizes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Startup Weekend is to simulate the process of going through a startup. You do not have to have a team already assembled. In fact it’s discouraged.  Startup Weekend is about encouraging new business ideas &amp;amp; innovation so you shouldn’t be walking in with a fully laid out business plan. For the other participants some of the joy is getting to work with people you may “know of” in the CLT startup community but haven’t actually had a chance to work with previously/professionally. The creative/collaborative energy of the team is one of the best experiences to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="pitching"&gt;Pitching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrive early-ish before 6pm. The food is quite good, last year it was Pure Pizza from 7th St Public Market. There are always vegetarian options (but not necessarily vegan or gluten free, unless you request them). When you arrive and register you’ll be given a color coded name tag. The colors change from year to year but each color associates to a developer, a designer and non-technical. Learn those color assignments because that will help you target who you want/need to talk to as you work the room before pitches start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you talk to people and identify their skills ask why they’re there. Some enjoy the creative process/want to try new skills, some want to be part of a company that will make a real go of it, others want their own pitch to get picked. Absolutely connect with the designers, because your team will really struggle without one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason to work the room beforehand is that everybody with an idea pitches. Once pitches are done, everyone votes and the 6 or so pitches/ideas that received the most votes are picked as that weekend’s startups. Everyone should then go work on one of those 6 ideas. So the reason to work the room early is twofold,  identify those with the skills you need for your team and to also solicit votes for your pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXeAUq891rU&amp;amp;list=PL1E88D9A00D73F7ED&amp;amp;index=1"&gt;last year’s pitches&lt;/a&gt; and compare those to the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://charlotte.startupweekend.org/category/meat-the-teams/"&gt;companies that were selected&lt;/a&gt;. During the pitch what will attract people is a genuinely interesting problem and a UNIQUE way of tackling it. Do not forget to say in your pitch the roles/talents your team needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="working"&gt;Working&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once on a team  you want to keep your focus on what is known as the minimum viable product (MVP). That is the product or process with the fewest number of features that demonstrate what the company does so that users can accomplish their goal. Having at least one graphic designer can help so that the user interface is well designed and enjoyable. If you have a second designer, creating mockups for the development team or the presentation for the judges can be a real strategic asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="presenting"&gt;Presenting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judges that participate in CSW are from the Charlotte community who’ve created and sold their own startups. What they want to see in Sunday’s pitch is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="validation-of-the-product"&gt;Validation of the Product&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure out if people are interested in your product as quickly as possible. Previous teams targeting products for the restaurant industry have gone out on Friday nights to talk to bar managers and customers. Don’t forget your fellow CSW participants, you can survey them. If you talk to potential customers and no one is eager for the solution, come up with a new idea! This happens a lot even into Saturday. Part of your team should make a website, a twitter account &amp;amp; a Facebook page for the company and fill them with marketing copy. Use all the free CSW goodies like .co domains, launchrock templates, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="addressable-market"&gt;Addressable Market&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The venture capitalists that typically are the judges like to see a 10x return on their investment. Let’s say your idea gets picked on Friday. At your presentation on Sunday when you go through what problem the company is trying to solve and how the solution does that there should be a part where you ask for X amount of money to start the company. For instance let’s say you ask for $100,000. So the judges will want to see that theoretically the company could earn at least $1,000,000 per yr. Let’s say the amount of money for your market is $1 billion. The cliche phrase is to get 1% of the $1 billion spent per year to use your app. The app’s income would be $10 million. Your addressable market is $1 billion, the return on investment is 99%. All of this is fake but it demonstrates the type of numbers &amp;amp; terminology the judges want to see used. Someone in the team will need to google the industry numbers and figure out the addressable market/ROI. If your addressable market is too small change the business model or the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="business-plan"&gt;Business Plan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonprofit doesn’t mean it has to lose money. Making money is a means of being sustainable and only a signal that what the company does provides value that customers want. Look at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.kiva.org/"&gt;http://www.kiva.org&lt;/a&gt; it has a social mission &amp;amp; investors are paid a return for their risk. Discuss why your product or business model is better than your competitors. If your product has no competitors you may be chasing a market no one wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup Weekend can be a tremendously rewarding experience when you are open to change. Your pitch may not be picked; join one of the selected teams who have an idea that is particularly challenging or who have members you don’t know. Your professional expertise may not be used; learn about an industry/vertical new to you or try new skills by filling in a missing role on your team. Most of all collaborate with your team members, you’re there to help each other build the best product &amp;amp; presentation. Like life, you’ll get out of Charlotte Startup Weekend what you put into it. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Spreading Happiness (Happygifs.co) Faster</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/spreading-happiness-faster/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/spreading-happiness-faster/</id>
    <published>2013-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T19:46:24-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vegan hotdogs lead to increased performance. Believe me or not, but it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual story was &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://joshuamauldin.com/"&gt;Joshua Mauldin&lt;/a&gt;, maker of iOS apps, websites and a lover of design and I to catch up at JJ Red Hot's for lunch. He created BlendConf's excellent t-shirt...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vegan hotdogs lead to increased performance. Believe me or not, but it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual story was &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://joshuamauldin.com/"&gt;Joshua Mauldin&lt;/a&gt;, maker of iOS apps, websites and a lover of design and I to catch up at JJ Red Hot's for lunch. He created BlendConf's excellent t-shirt swag thru his &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://neuedist.com/"&gt;Neuedist&lt;/a&gt; project. He told me his new playground is &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://happygifs.co"&gt;happygifs.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website serves a happiness inspiring animated gif. Who doesn't want to share or show their happiness around the holidays? If the first load doesn't please you Scrooge McDuck, hit "Get Happier" and try again. Joshua and I talked of our mutual obsession of page speed and that it wasn't as fast as he would like. Let's see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="where"&gt;Where&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the performance of the website, we want to take measurements as close as possible to the server. This is a quick test, so we'll do our best. Geographic distance typically leads to more network hops. More hops means a slower experience for that user, so let's find where happygifs.co lives. &lt;code&gt;traceroute www.happygifs.co&lt;/code&gt; shows the site hosted with DigitalOcean, whose &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/questions/datacenters-where-are-these-located-is-there-a-plan-for-the-data-center-in-asia-singapore"&gt;datacenter is in New York&lt;/a&gt;. Of the webpagetest.org testing locations, Virginia is closest. Here's the median of a 5 test run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
 th, td { text-align: center; vertical-align: middle; }
 .header { text-align: center; vertical-align: middle; background-color: lightgrey; }
 .invisible { border: 0px; }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;table class="table table-bordered table-hover table-condensed table-responsive"&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th class="invisible"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Load Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;First Byte&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Start Render&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/a/webpagetest.org/docs/using-webpagetest/metrics/speed-index" target="_blank"&gt;Speed Index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
   &lt;/thead&gt;
   &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td align="right"&gt;First View&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.692s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.164s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.590s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;898&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.692s&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td valign="right"&gt;Repeat View&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.127s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.125s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.303s&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;540&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.127s&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what"&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the detailed results linked below you'll see all the tests  ran using Chrome on Cable modem speed. How did I decide to use Chrome? By consulting &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#desktop+mobile+tablet-browser_version-na-quarterly-201304-201304-bar"&gt;the most popular browswers this quarter by Version &amp;amp; Platform for North Ameria&lt;/a&gt;. Other is a combination of everything else and it likely had such a large share since I requested stats including mobile. Chrome did not have the largest individual share but combined it's share was larger than IE's. Not every  browser is available in every location so sometimes it's difficult to get consist analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="when"&gt;When&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data seems to be have as you would expect. A repeat view is faster that the first view because the browser should be caching page elements. Yet, the devil is in the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.webpagetest.org/result/131218_JH_V8E/"&gt;Look at the individual results in the 5 test run&lt;/a&gt;. In the screen shots you'll see a different featured image on each request. Thus the runs were all first views. You should notice there's a high degree of variability in the results. The average is masking the range in page load from 1.688 to 9.178 seconds. As you look at the waterfall diagrams you should notice that the variability is happening for 2 different reasons. Either the gif is the slowest page element or the advertisements are. Unfortunately the third party APIs and ad delivery networks are out of Joshua's control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how"&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole time we've been in the weeds, let's now look at those large colored letter grades at the top. Greenlit A's all around for "Time to First Byte", "Keep-Alive Enabled", and "Compress Transfer". "Compress Images" is not applicable so there's no rating, "Effective use of CDN" is an X and there's an F for "Cache static content".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://toolbar.netcraft.com/site_report?url=happygifs.co#last_reboot"&gt;quick query of Netcraft&lt;/a&gt; tells us the site is running nginx 1.2.1 so we know what web server directives to use. TTF is  text so we can compress it. Add the following to &lt;code&gt;/etc/nginx/nginx.conf&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;gzip_types&lt;/code&gt; to cover the webfonts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;font/opentype font/truetype application/x-font-ttf application/vnd.ms-fontobject
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web server should have the correct MIME type to deliver the custom webfonts. Add to &lt;code&gt;/etc/nginx/mime.types&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;font/opentype                  ott;
application/font-woff          woff;
application/x-font-ttf         ttf;
application/vnd.ms-fontobject  eot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the fonts served and compressed, now we tell browsers to cache all the static assets. The settings are not the most aggressive possible, instead caching for a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;location ~* \.(css|eot|gif|ico|jpg|jpeg|jpe|js|png|svg|svgz|tif|tiff|ttf|woff)$ {
  expires 2592000s;
  add_header Pragma public;
  add_header Cache-Control "public, must-revalidate, proxy-revalidate";
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there are a few page elements that we may be able to offload from Joshua's site. We can look up if the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://cdnjs.com/"&gt;css and javascript libraries are available on a CDN&lt;/a&gt;.  Bootstrap may not be applicable if he's customized it. Here's the URLs to use in his &lt;code&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; directives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/animate.css/3.1.0/animate.min.css
//netdna.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/3.1.1/css/bootstrap.min.css
//netdna.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/3.1.1/js/bootstrap.min.js
//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/fastclick/1.0.0/fastclick.min.js
//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery-cookie/1.4.1/jquery.cookie.min.js
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the application to store the gifs in Amazon's S3/Cloudfront or a &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.cdnplanet.com/cdns/"&gt;competitor&lt;/a&gt; CDN could be the next step. With the logs from the site we could forecast his costs to help pick a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="who"&gt;Who&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefitiary is everyone. Faster websites makes us all happy even when the content isn't animated gifs of adorable kittens frockling. A better user experience is what Google rewards in their search results. If you're a website owner it is in your best interest to care about speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Parallels of DevOps &amp; Yoga</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/parallels-of-devops-yoga/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/parallels-of-devops-yoga/</id>
    <published>2013-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T20:17:18-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a job that made me unhappy until one day I quit. No plan, no interviews scheduled, no idea what I desired to work on next, not even sure if I wanted to stay in technology I was so burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the summer off, dropped 5% of my body fat,...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a job that made me unhappy until one day I quit. No plan, no interviews scheduled, no idea what I desired to work on next, not even sure if I wanted to stay in technology I was so burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the summer off, dropped 5% of my body fat, put on 15 lbs of muscle, my workouts were my only schedule. I'd been practicing yoga for a couple of years as a complement and recovery to my athletic endeavours. But this period seemed the right time to take yoga teacher training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During those nine months of training our class had lots of discussions. In one a fellow trainee described an article he read on the frequency of practicing yoga and its benefits.  The central idea was that doing something more often made you better at it faster and cited a study of Korean War fighter pilots. I stopped listening to my classmate as the bomb went off in my head that he had described to class the OODA loop (Orient, Observe, Decide &amp;amp; Act).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Boyd's OODA loop is one of the founding ideas  behind release early &amp;amp; often philosophy.  This ideology grew into Agile Development in software development and Lean Startup in business. Where does does DevOps come into play with yoga?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a quick rehash. DevOps is the merging of the business and the development process. As software changes from a packaged product at a store to an online service, software development is evolving.  Business development or product managers used to decide what to build.  They then told the developers who handed the code to system administrators to deploy to servers. Now customers dictate features. The faster a company finds those customers and responds to their needs the faster it has a sustainable product. What does any of that have to do with yoga? My axiom is that yoga &amp;amp; devops have the same goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="union"&gt;Union&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of work by scholars of Eastern and Western backgrounds about what is yoga the union of and its philosophy. I am not going to summarize those arguments. Let me go with the assumption that most Americans experience yoga as exercise. While yoga can be a great workout many people I know who who go appreciate getting out of their head. The mental noise of the day quiets as the sense of the body being the vessel of the mind blurs. It's a feeling of connection. We are so much more than the sum of our parts, whether it is our intellect, our corporal selves or as individuals. When someone knows that from within they can be so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this same blurring we desire out of DevOps. Developers that understand the servers they're designing and deploying applications onto. Systems administrators that are writing code to respond to customer demands. Sometimes in a yoga class when we feel the most taxed the mind starts talking to the tiny voices that are our heart. These conversations that break down the us versus them dynamic of an IT team are huge. Teams that connect, speak the same language of code, and serve customers can be so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="knowing"&gt;Knowing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a lifeguard. When you are drowning, breathing is both the  goal and hard to do. Starting a yoga practice can feel the same. The teacher may be saying inhale and exhale but you're just trying to keep up. Some poses you'll love because it allows you to catch your breath. In time, you'll notice the poses where you hold your breath. Maybe you figure out not breathing makes those poses more difficult. Maybe you notice how you don't breathe sitting in traffic or during important meetings. Maybe you inhale. How's your day going? Check your breathe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I heard of the Monitorama conference it had sold out. Monitoring is awesome. I understand some hate monitoring because monitoring means an alert of an emergency and something has to be fixed. Some may love graphs, I love the answers monitoring provides. It tells me if server capacity can be reduced to save money or does this code need to be refactored because it takes too long to run. Are customers using the new features that were rolled out? How's the business doing? Check your monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="agility"&gt;Agility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any of your friends said "I can't do yoga, I'm not flexibile"? Mine have. For whatever reason people sometimes define themselves by what they don't do. The beauty of language is the nuance and subtlety between words. In common practice we may think of agility as the same as being flexible. Your friend may not be flexible in this moment but that is not a permanent state. Regular yoga can improve flexibility. The greater benefit of practice may be increased agility, the ability to move without thought. Getting out of the head, feeling a connected self that does not labor on reasons not to act that's being agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical people are fun. We like debating nuance and subtlety at times. There is Agile with a capital letter a implying one of the formal agile processes. There is agile with a lower case that is squishier, less structured. It incorporates what is needed without the rigidity that does not fit the situation. DevOps takes neither side with it's ship it philosophy. Is a production system  broken? Fix it so it doesn't happen again and get better. Ship, learn, iterate that's agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="perfection"&gt;Perfection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our American culture focuses on perfection. People often feel their yoga poses have to be perfect. They love the poses that are easy to them, hate the ones they struggle with. Yet American's embrace of failure has led it to be an economic powerhouse. The US's bankruptcy laws encourage trying new business ventures. When they don't work out, all parties move on. You see this in venture capitalists that ask what founders learned from their ventures that fold. Tell someone what you've learned from poses you disliked than show off a pose that's perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about DevOps is its ship it philosophy. Combined with monitoring the team learns far more, faster, and they become more agile. It is a practice that reinforces itself. Rather than hold back a new feature for an application for the usual delays, ship the smallest piece. See what the team learns. Often you'll find people want the features they need than the feature that's perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="breaking-habits"&gt;Breaking Habits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we feel connected, and we know how we feel because we know how we're breathing, we can be decisive. Rather than hung up on feeling what we must do or can not do, we do. The OODA loop of observe, orient, decide, act is what my classmate was touching on that day. The faster and more times we go through this loop the more negative thoughts or feelings we get out of ourselves. Once those are out, space opens for what can  be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a teacher that before showing how to get into any new pose she would show how to fall out of it. We would see there wasn't far to fall. Sure we still struggled in it the first time but I didn't fall. The second time through I knew what to do and fell pretty quick. The third time I knew where failure happened and corrected for it. Then keeping my breath, not overthinking nor worrying to make it perfect, held the pose. OODA loop in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where is your organization in incorporating DevOps? Do siloed development and operations teams now collaborate at the start of new projects? Maybe they swap code as projects evolve. The technical team and business team are sharing data to improve product or processes. New insights get released to customers to test. Many will say DevOps is the lastest IT fad. Others many counter it doesn't work in the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time through a process is uncomfortable. The set up of the tooling can feel burdensome. If you don't go through a process first you cannot incorporate the lessons into the second time. You'll see the process didn't take as long. Perhaps the third time through there is a change and it's handled fast. OODA loop in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tldr"&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga and DevOps are used in different environments but their outcomes and goals are similar. The lessons of one can be carried into the other. If you're a developer sitting at a desk go take a yoga class. Did being in class feel like your software development or deploy process ? If you're a yoga practitioner and now you're curious about writing code, leave a comment and I'll show how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Claire Danes Taught Me about DevOps</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scottelundgren.com/what-claire-danes-taught-me-about-devops/"/>
    <id>http://www.scottelundgren.com/what-claire-danes-taught-me-about-devops/</id>
    <published>2013-11-02T01:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-08-16T20:16:34-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Scott E Lundgren</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In July my voice teacher let me know that Homeland was looking for yoga practitioners for a scene. Between the morning when she mentioned it and the afternoon when she filled me in on the details to apply, seemingly twitter, facebook and even lunch...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In July my voice teacher let me know that Homeland was looking for yoga practitioners for a scene. Between the morning when she mentioned it and the afternoon when she filled me in on the details to apply, seemingly twitter, facebook and even lunch time TV news had spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I first intended to try out as a lark now seemed daunting. With a little encouragement from my teacher, I applied, and was cast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Homeland - The Yoga Play Script" class="img-rounded img-responsive pull-right" alt="" src="/images/homeland-script-2013-16-07.jpg" /&gt;
The morning I showed up on set I was promoted from extra to stand-in because I resembled one of the actors. As a stand-in, you're on set to watch as the actors rehearse the scene, the actors &amp;amp; directors discussing blocking (where they'll stand &amp;amp; move across the set), then (surprise!) stand-in for the principal actor while lighting and sound make their adjustments for shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actors come back, you as stand-in get out of the way, and the crew shoots the scene. There isn't much to do, so it affords a lot of time to observe. That's how I noticed the production of a television episode is a lot like software development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A television episode is like your web application in that the episode is a collection of scenes like features that seek to provide value. In the case of the episode the end value is entertainment. As a television series seeks an audience the success of a software product is determined by serving a user base. Each scene of an episode can be defined as a code sprint, as each scene moves a narrative forward the goal of a sprint is a well defined result such as particular features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of DevOps what comes to mind? For me the primary tenants are a culture of operations, development and business communicating. One also monitors everything, use the information to get better and adopt  code as infrastructure so processes are repeatable, testable and move toward continuous deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How a television episode is made is more about their process and their people and this is the core message of the devops movement. Television shows have ratings to monitor their interaction with their audience hopefully you have monitoring not just for your infrastructure but every business aspect that's critical to your application's success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one afternoon I saw tape marked onto a floor to note where an actor would stand for their next shot, chrome trim of cars sprayed with a matte film to prevent distracting reflections, and entire system of fake licenses plates depending on desired location &amp;amp; context (i.e.: principal characters, multiple federal agencies, general local MD/DC/VA license plates) just as any web application from the infrastructure code to front end assets are going to have hundreds of details to track or change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a stand-in I was literally a mock object for camera angles &amp;amp; lightening adjustments to be set. Sounds a lot like writing test driven development doesn't ? Once your test cases are set up and you're creating the actual features, we know writing software doesn't always go right the first time. The same happens to actors, sometimes they flub the scene and break the build so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As developers we iterate until our features pass. When there are multiple bad takes I saw no one on set crucify who made the mistake; I think it's important part of DevOps culture that instead of finger pointing the issue is addressed and everyone goes on. Another aspect of filming is that their process is repeatable, capturing another take on a scene is not considered a failure. Sometimes the crew kick off another build by reshooting the scene just so to make sure they got it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure my metaphor may break down in that film &amp;amp; tv production is incredibly manual in the numbers of people that are employed where software teams following agile processes can be be incredibly small. But hear me out. If we take scenes within an episode as equivalent to our code sprint, then easily we can draw the Director as product owner who is executing on the episode or product vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the episode/web application is the end product how does everyone else fit? Without writers creating a script, or designers &amp;amp; front end engineers there's nothing with which for the audience or users to interact. Where do actors and developers come in? They are the creators shaping the execution, using their creativity to give life to that episode or product. If an actor without a stage is just two people mumbling at each other, code without deployment are bits on a hard drive. Sound, lights, camera crew are the specialists of networking, security, and infrastructure in deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no wall of that's acting &amp;amp; that's production just as DevOps embraces as we've moved from shipped stand alone software to continuously deployed web applications. Wardrobe and props are functions that help actors best embody their character just as building internal environments of development &amp;amp; staging or the quality assurance teams help the team create their best product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Yoga Play Screenshot" class="img-rounded img-responsive pull-left" alt="" src="/images/homeland-screenshot-2013-10-27.jpg" /&gt;
As an extra waiting to see if you were cut from a scene feels a bit like waiting to see if your pull request gets accepted into a major open source project. With this past Sunday's airing of Episode 5, I was able to capture a screenshot of me in the green shirt straightening up &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.8thstreetstudio.com"&gt;8th Street Studio&lt;/a&gt; as the actor I stood in for left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I learn about DevOps spending the day alternating between 2 feet and 20 feet from Claire Danes? That to win an Emmy and put out a great episode/product you need a testable, repeatable process and a talented team around you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
