<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Scott Lundgren's RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lawful Dev in a Chaotic Ops World 😼 Everything is an Experiment]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 01:41:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Lessons from Remote: Office Not Required in a Global Pandemic]]></title><description><![CDATA[It has been one year and one month since the World Health Organization declared COVID-19 a pandemic. Therefore there is no surprise that…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/lessons-from-remote-office-not-required-in-a-global-pandemic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/lessons-from-remote-office-not-required-in-a-global-pandemic/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It has been one year and one month since the World Health Organization declared COVID-19 a pandemic. Therefore there is no surprise that searches on Google for the seven-and-a-half-year-old book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3x9h3o1&quot;&gt;Remote: Office Not Required by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt; dramatically jumped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 1200px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/29114/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 44.33333333333333%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAJCAYAAAAywQxIAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAABPUlEQVQoz22S3ZKDIAyFff9H3Ku9qKNYsVpAQAhnE1w6drvMnDETki8/2G02QqkJ8zxXKaUQY8T1lFKQc4a1FiGEl++q5usKZRDRB0CUUnqzBSqxf0HXvM5w1XVdcRwHjDGvLkRaa+z7Du89lmWpvis05VTzpFhT55zDtm0IPiCGiFt/q6CWJABRsyV+miYMw8DFXfXJiqSoqGvkI3k8zB3jvcfu9n/3JJJkmULpHmrpETmPL2oDAu9KIRCvYmaYj+Zjj/8tv52YLPqV15JqBnN4h2DgsmfcXQNRrUa/AKJ34PmArHI+pLKA5nwBZr7rxFh8wWhzbd1EqpdiFzrtmCW4YA0Ed5xfkRQdTWboCZf4usPZshzhGQoGcyY9TMCD/1HP48id3gnjU2IPfOmE2yZTyXSEbx2xcpdHJvwAa0bA8ZFoIDcAAAAASUVORK5CYII=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Google Trends Search Traffic for Remote: Office Not Required from April 2013 to April 20&quot;
        title=&quot;Google Trends Search Traffic for Remote: Office Not Required from April 2013 to April 20&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/c1b63/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/5a46d/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png 300w,
/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/0a47e/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png 600w,
/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/c1b63/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png 1200w,
/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/d61c2/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png 1800w,
/static/21c8bd5f28424daf6c82a600c25c2a28/29114/remote-office-not-required-google-trend.png 1920w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the pandemic was for many a sudden experiment in remote work, let us go chapter by chapter. I will examine one concept for each chapter: the promise, reality, and results.  I will acknowledge the bias that the upper half of the K-shaped economic recovery where people who were more likely to be affluent and white were able to apply the lessons from the book. These realities and results are subjective, the outcomes of decades of policy and privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structurally, Remote: Office Not Required is divided into seven chapters, eight if you count the short conclusion. The first three chapters help the individual make the case to their management to allow remote working. Chapters four through six discuss adjustments to your workflow and corporate culture so working remotely is as productive as an office. The seventh chapter is a condensed guide of best practices for a remote employee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 1: The Time is Right for Remote Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter was the opening salvo in the argument for remote work. It laid out the amount of time wasted commuting, the downsides of living in superstar cities, and the folly that superstar cities are the only places for talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The luxury privilege of the next 20 years will be to leave the city. Not as it’s leashed servant in a suburb, but to wherever one wants.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unclear. Given the ability to work remotely by employers and historically low interest rates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/millions-americans-moved-during-pandemic-most-aren-t-looking-back-n1252633&quot;&gt;many people moved&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/02/04/as-the-pandemic-persisted-financial-pressures-became-a-bigger-factor-in-why-americans-decided-to-move/&quot;&gt;Some moved for economic necessity&lt;/a&gt;, while others &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redfin.com/news/second-home-demand-record-high/&quot;&gt;bought second houses in vacation destinations&lt;/a&gt;. It seems &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.governing.com/assessments/Where-Americans-Are-Moving-and-Why-They-Really-Are-Doing-It.html&quot;&gt;few people moved to lower their risk of catching the virus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remains to be seen. Will those who purchased second homes move there permanently? Given such cheap capital, these houses could be investments for future Airbnb income when travel returns. I am curious how many people whose lives may no longer be tethered to a particular place of work might opt for a traveling lifestyle. Will &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_nomad&quot;&gt;digital nomadism&lt;/a&gt; no longer be dominated by twenty-something Instagram influencers? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 2: Dealing with Excuses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subtopics of this chapter are the objections one would hear from an office traditionalist: 1. homes are full of distractions, 2. big businesses are not remote and 3. only the office is secure. In a pandemic, for many businesses, remote work became a necessity and not a luxury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;People&apos;s homes are full of distractions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homes became full of distractions because they were full of everyone. COVID-19 being airborne, schools shut down. Thus with no childcare, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/01/from-jobs-to-pay-the-coronavirus-pandemic-has-hurt-women.html&quot;&gt;statistically, women left the workforce in droves&lt;/a&gt;. Two adults having zoom calls at the same time could have chosen headphones or to work in different rooms to hear themselves think. But add in remote schooling for children, and no wonder &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizjournals.com/pittsburgh/news/2021/04/02/how-the-home-office-is-changing.html&quot;&gt;home office renovations exploded&lt;/a&gt;. So is the traditionalist correct and remote cannot work long term? With vaccines, schools reopening, and childcare returning that argument falls apart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big businesses became remote. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsideonline.com/2416265/rei-selling-bellevue-headquarters-remote-work&quot;&gt;REI sold its headquarters&lt;/a&gt; in favor of smaller spaces, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hrblog.spotify.com/2021/02/12/introducing-working-from-anywhere/&quot;&gt;Spotify is going remote&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/jpmorgan-salesforce-join-growing-list-of-firms-dumping-office-space-11617096603&quot;&gt;JPMorgan and Salesforce are dumping office space&lt;/a&gt;. Big businesses are thinking about how to operate going forward. This has ramifications as property taxes on central business districts (CBD) are income sources for cities, but I&apos;ll visit that idea another time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves the antiquated idea that only the office can be secure. I hope your employer or yourself are not relying on physical security (ie: access to the laptop) for securing your work product or customer&apos;s data. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero_trust_security_model&quot;&gt;Zero Trust Security Model&lt;/a&gt; provides an excellent basis for a fully remote workforce with wide implementation and vendor offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct. Every counter-argument DDH wrote in this chapter was gold of why and how remote work is achievable. Even if you or your organization isn&apos;t executing all these ideas, rereading this chapter could be a source of inspiration to improve one percent more over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 3: How to Collaborate Remotely&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter gets into the transformations an organization needs to make for remote work to be as best as it can. Surprise! The answer is not to add Slack or Teams or whatever Google has renamed their G Suite communication tool this quarter. David Heinemeier Hansson and Jason Fried&apos;s advice is about schedules, collaboration tools that seem quaint seven years later, transitioning slowly (unfortunately the pandemic did not allow for that), and minimizing meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In systems design, there’s the notion of a Single Point of Failure or SPoF. Much of the work required to achieve high reliability goes into finding and removing SPoFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter suggests that remote work would draw attention to SPOF&apos;s by embracing remote work as an exercise in disaster preparedness. An unscheduled pandemic was certainly a disaster exercise for which many were unprepared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working required more email, instant response to chat messages, back-to-back-to-back Zoom meetings. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90625371/is-zooms-ux-sexist&quot;&gt;Staring at a screen caused fatigue, especially in women&lt;/a&gt;. Remove physical and psychologically recharging activities like visiting friends, club sports, or church and add on family care. Maybe you, like me, learned the single point of failure was ourselves. Tools like a VPN and calendar invites didn&apos;t support the other struggles of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remains to be seen. This month, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2021/04/02/success/linkedin-paid-week-off/index.html&quot;&gt;LinkedIn paid staff a week off to disconnect&lt;/a&gt;. Going forward there are opportunities for those who have burned out or heading toward burnout. Try to recognize when your energy ebbs and flows then apply those rhythms to your work schedule. Maybe a 7 am to 11 am sprint in the mornings, a long break in the mid-day to refresh or connect with family, and then a 2 pm to 6 pm session to button up the day. It is the same amount of time as 9-5 pm, only shifted. Longer-term there is a market for better collaborative tools that best replicate the ease of being in a room together without the time, stress, and greenhouse gases of flying there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 4: Beware the Dragons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DHH writes the most practical advice here, extolling techniques and methods for a successful remote employee. Surprisingly, these principles are valuable in a non-remote context, but in a remote context, they are critical: do not work too much or in an uncomfortable space, interact with people outside of work, exercise, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cabin fever is real, and remote workers are more susceptible to it than those forced into an office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&apos;t take Project MKUltra (a CIA experiment involving sensory deprivation and isolation) to guess that asking people to work remotely without being able to go anywhere or see anyone during winter caused widespread burnout, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/11/us/covid-burnout-mayors.html&quot;&gt;even for mayors&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct. Following the tips in this chapter can help you to keep good physical and emotional health as a human being - not a mouse hitting a KPI button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 5: Hiring and Keeping the Best&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter five is similar to chapter four. That is, the lessons in it are about fundamental principles of finding excellent people to join a team, whether remote or non-remote. Prioritize written communication, diversity, and personal development. There is no one weird trick that will help you identify the best talent. This is also the chapter where DHH and Fried make the case about paying employees what they&apos;re worth, not just to their cost of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great remote workers are simply great workers &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/03/business/pandemic-burnout-productivity.html&quot;&gt;The burnout is real&lt;/a&gt;. One in four employees is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/chriswestfall/2021/04/06/survey-shows-massive-post-pandemic-shift-in-store-for-workers/?sh=737a8d8b632b&quot;&gt;considering changing jobs when the pandemic is over&lt;/a&gt;. As companies move to a more remote workforce, the remote employees can&apos;t be considered less part of the culture or promotion track. A friend of mine was hired during the pandemic at a national financial firm. When they asked for coaching on the promotion process, their management said to take mentors to lunch. My friend left the company. Because management couldn&apos;t think past the pre-pandemic culture centralized in a corporate campus where meeting mentors was easy. One bright spot is that if organizations weave remote employees into their culture, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90525652/can-remote-work-live-up-to-its-potential-to-change-workplace-diversity&quot;&gt;hiring remote could accelerate hiring diversity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Fried&apos;s points are all correct. Yet guessing how these principles will be applied in the future feels like a 50% chance of being wrong and a 50% chance I&apos;m not correct. Between employers wanting staff back in the office for &quot;reasons&quot; and employees wanting to retain some aspect of remote to reducing commute times and more work/life balance, I think it&apos;ll be a pendulum. The questions are which group gets the swing started and how far the pendulum swings back over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 6: Managing Remote Workers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In chapter 6, the authors apply their experience in the open-source movement to offer insights on how to create a culture in which decentralized workers can thrive. Key ingredients are leveraging intrinsic motivation, allowing easy access to everyone who wants to contribute, and creating opportunities to collaborate in person. Other broadly applicable good advice: manage outputs instead of people in chairs, and encourage the removal of roadblocks instead of building a fiefdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because you don’t have a permanent office or not everyone is working out of one, that’s no reason not to get together every now and then. In fact, it’s almost mandatory to do so occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t know what reality is right now. This chapter recommends regular meetups. Not just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/your-corporate-retreat-is-onbut-its-going-to-be-weirder-11615753659&quot;&gt;a virtual corporate retreat over zoom&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps twice a year the company gets together to discuss projects, have show n&apos; tell and talk about the health of the business, and generally build company culture. In between, the chapter suggests colocating for a sprint to finish a difficult project before the deadline. How this unknown state gets worked out as companies adjust post-pandemic is the essence of this chapter and there are no answers yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remains to be seen. Management happens in the context of culture and culture &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketplace.org/2021/04/14/can-company-culture-survive-zoom/&quot;&gt;is not transmitted through the employee handbook&lt;/a&gt;. It’s transmitted through relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Chapter 7: Life as a Remote Worker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrelling towards a conclusion, chapter seven begins to weave the material together. Touching on chapter one, nomadic freedom or a change of scenery can look like scheduling your day to work partly at home, partly at a library, and partly at a cafe all in the same day in the same town as much as different countries each month. This approach to controlling your environment as much as your tasks (catch up, collaboration, or serious work) builds upon chapter four where you optimize for your workflow. Part of this strategy is using routine to demark to your psyche when it&apos;s time to work and when to relax. Lastly, the authors mention that separation can come in device form: a laptop for work, a tablet for home (do not add your work email account to it). Chapter 6 gets touched on again by reminding us that motivation is the fuel of intellectual work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Promise:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone has a spare bedroom to turn into a home office, but that doesn’t mean you can’t work remotely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One option of not having an existing space in a home to convert into a home office has been to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.charlotteobserver.com/charlottefive/c5-around-town/article250026039.html&quot;&gt;add a shed office to the backyard&lt;/a&gt;. With a recent IPO, you may think big brands WeWork or Regus dominate coworking. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://connectedremag.com/real-estate-news/cre/coworking/smaller-co-working-companies-could-struggle-in-post-covid-world/&quot;&gt;80% of the coworking market is small to medium-sized operators&lt;/a&gt;. It&apos;s kind of quaint that the book explains co-working or subleasing a single office from another existing company. Of course, there&apos;s always a coffee shop, not that I would recommend a Zoom meeting there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct. I picked out co-working as the chapter&apos;s main idea because the ramifications of co-working and commercial real estate in the post-Corona world are fascinating. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wearehygge.com/blog/zero-to-ten-with-garrett-tichy-will-coworking-survive/&quot;&gt;Small co-working companies may struggle&lt;/a&gt; because of limited reach and cash to get through the months as customers stayed home. Larger firms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2020/10/24/wework-coworking-coronavirus-office-commercial-real-estate/&quot;&gt;WeWork may thrive&lt;/a&gt; as they renegotiated leases and expanded locations as corporate clients exited their long-term office leases to have flexibility. With empty offices and a drop in business travel leading to empty hotels that could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/16/realestate/empty-office-buildings-hotels.html&quot;&gt;lead to a shuffle of offices into housing, hotels to housing, and hotels turning into short-term offices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How well did Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson predict the future in Remote: Office Not Required? Four out of seven of their ideas were correct. Their recommended approach is the way that things have played out. Of the chapters whose recommendations I said remains to be seen is a common thread is people. The argument has been made that the COVID-19 pandemic is an accelerant. Perhaps people have not yet caught up to the ideas. As time goes on, the correctness may increase.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Girl Develop It Launches Charlotte Chapter]]></title><description><![CDATA[My hope is you’ll help me get fired from a job I want. Let me explain. At BlendConf 2013 Ashe Dryden gave a talk on the challenges of…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/girl-develop-it-charlotte-launch/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/girl-develop-it-charlotte-launch/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My hope is you’ll help me get fired from a job I want. Let me explain. At &lt;a href=&quot;../blend-conference-2013/&quot;&gt;BlendConf 2013&lt;/a&gt; Ashe Dryden gave a talk on the challenges of entering the technology field. Those challenges affect disproportionately any one that is not a white, straight, single male. She ended on a list of action items. One was to increase education and access. Among the organizations she mentioned was Girl Develop It that just started a chapter in Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attendance of the launch event was pure coincidence. At a networking event one of the founders asked me to come. The response to Girl Develop It Charlotte&apos;s formation has been great. It is one the largest technical group meetups in Charlotte with over a 120 members! If you want to stay abreast of their events join &lt;a href=&quot;https://meetup.com/Girl-Develop-It-Charlotte-NC/&quot;&gt;GDI Charlotte&apos;s meetup group&lt;/a&gt;; it is free and easy. Or follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GDICharlotte&quot;&gt;GDICharlotte&lt;/a&gt; on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’m ahead of myself. What is Girl Develop It? It is an organization to provide affordable classes to women who want to learn software development. They provide both through mentorship and hands on instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the launch event there was great food, cookies (always a plus!), and a photo booth. Founders Crystal and Steph explained how the group formed out of Charlotte’s User Experience meet up. Their goal is to offer classes that focus on programming skills and knowledge, starting off with the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classes will cost around $10/hr. That’s an incredible value for in person training. A typical class will run 2 hours on a weeknight for 4 weeks so the total cost would be $80. They recognize women often have the role of caregiver so they are working to provide child care during sessions. Besides core classes there will be workshops of other technical topics to meet the skill levels of the group. If you want to teach, teachers get 50% of fees. For instance, a 4 hour workshop with 10 people would pay $200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the points she hit was how important they feel it is that women teach women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel closed the night talking about her own experiences as a developer. The empowerment of that quote is two-fold. One to prove that women are in the field, but two as an avenue for women in the field to gain experience public speaking. From this mutually enriching environment they hope to create mentoring and networking among members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to my opening statement. I’d love to teach a class I’m calling Your Friend Command Line. It could give a comfortable and powerful understanding of command line so students have a choice in their workflow. I believe I can make the topic fun and less intimidating. Right now I&apos;m figuring out a curriculum and how long the class might be. Yet, I also understand that I should not be the one to teach it. The best outcome might be I teach it once, you encourage a woman to join &amp;#x26; she shares the joy.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hacking Nan & Byron's Beet Burger]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hacking has had a bad wrap for over 40 years. Yet today Facebook is on Hackerway Way and Charlotte’s hosted a hackathon for a second year…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/hacking-nan-byrons-beet-burger/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/hacking-nan-byrons-beet-burger/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hacking has had a bad wrap for over 40 years. Yet today Facebook is on Hackerway Way and &lt;a href=&quot;https://detailedblock.com/2014/04/18/hackathonclt-planned-larger-event-2014/&quot;&gt;Charlotte’s hosted a hackathon for a second year&lt;/a&gt;. While hacking still means rule breaking to some, the phrase means a clever solution too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food hacking is still a favorite activity of mine because when I’m dining out I’m looking to bring flavors into my own kitchen. In November at a charity event Lyft held at &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://5churchcharlotte.com/&quot;&gt;5 Church&lt;/a&gt;, I enjoyed the beet burger sliders that were among the buffet. It excited me when that restaurant group opened the casual &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nanandbyrons.com/&quot;&gt;Nan &amp;#x26; Bryon&lt;/a&gt;’s with their Beet Burger as a main course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been eating vegetarian dinners and there are only so many times one can enjoy a black bean burger. &lt;a href=&quot;https://eatmorecowbell.com/&quot;&gt;Cowbell&lt;/a&gt;’s Shankar Burger of curry pinto &amp;#x26; faro is pretty unique, but still is mash of ingredients and cooked. The problem with that approach it is that it has a certain mouth texture that can be unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatness of the beet burger is that it is whole, with a resistance for your teeth and great meaty mouth feel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;htop and Chrome Dev Tools my normal investigative weapons were set aside to unlock Nan &amp;#x26; Byron’s beet burger. First I started doing research. Google searching “beet burger recipe” turned up some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenkitchenstories.com/grilled-beet-burgers/&quot;&gt;tasty sounding&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#x26; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sproutedkitchen.com/home/2013/3/26/smoky-beet-burgers.html&quot;&gt;looking&lt;/a&gt; recipes. But they all boiled down to the same “cook beets, shred beets, add beans, mix, form patties, cook” formula. Unfortunately that wasn’t the mouth feel I was hunting. So I started looking into other ways to cook beets because I’ve never prepared them before. I had no idea what to do to them. Then I found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://allrecipes.com/recipe/beet-salad-with-goat-cheese/&quot;&gt;beet salad recipe&lt;/a&gt; and how to make this delicious treat became became clear. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Nan &amp;#x26; Byron&apos;s Beet Burger by Scott Lundgren&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nan &amp;#x26; Byron&apos;s Beet burger is a vegetarian alternative that has great meaty mouth feel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;PREP TIME:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;COOK TIME:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;TOTAL TIME:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;15 Min&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;30 Min&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;45 Min&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Yield:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Category:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Cuisine:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;4 sandwiches&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Vegetarian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Bake&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;American&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 beets, medium, scrubbed, peeled, sliced in 1/4” thick discs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 buns, hawaiian or wheat, your preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 small red onion, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 small avocado, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cp panko breading or rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 oz goat cheese, plain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tblsp sunflower oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arugula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven, 400 degrees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On an aluminum foil sheet, layout the beets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baste the beets with 1 tblsp olive or sunflower oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 10 min, flip the beets to the other side&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 20 min, pull them out of the oven, let cool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dip beets in panko breading or rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warm up a pan over medium high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add 1 tblsp olive or sunflower oil to the pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fry the beets for 3 minutes on each side&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove beets to a plate lined with a paper towel to drain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spread goat cheese on the bottom bun, cover with arugula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place 3-4 beets to cover the bottom bun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top beets with onion &amp;#x26; avocado slices, serve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Win Charlotte Startup Weekend]]></title><description><![CDATA[Below is a repost written to encourage others to be at Charlotte Startup Weekend Participating in Charlotte’s Startup Weekend (CSW) may not…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/how-to-win-charlotte-startup-weekend/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/how-to-win-charlotte-startup-weekend/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Below is a repost written to encourage others to be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte.startupweekend.org/&quot;&gt;Charlotte Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participating in Charlotte’s Startup Weekend (CSW) may not lead to startup fame, cash or prizes. What spending the weekend at CSW will lead to is an understanding of getting an idea from nothing to something, meeting some incredibly talented people, and potentially discovering talents you didn’t know you had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed the first two CSWs and signed up in Fall 2011. My teammates &amp;#x26; I on &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2011/11/06/cribsheet-baby-mood-tracking-with-a-sense-of-humor-charlotte-startup-weekend/&quot;&gt;Cribsheet&lt;/a&gt; won and did &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2011/11/30/cribsheet-receives-global-recognition/&quot;&gt;gain some notoriety&lt;/a&gt;. The following Spring 2012 the team I was on &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte.startupweekend.org/2012/05/06/meet-the-teams-my-autopilot/&quot;&gt;My Autopilot&lt;/a&gt; didn’t win, but it was an inaugural member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://revtechlabs.com/&quot;&gt;RevTech Labs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://detailedblock.com/2012/07/14/autopilot-receives-angel-investment/&quot;&gt;received a cash investment&lt;/a&gt;. So for Spring 2013 I wrote the following advice to prep &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/katie_levans&quot;&gt;Katie Levans&lt;/a&gt; whose &lt;a href=&quot;http://plateshare.org/&quot;&gt;PlateShare&lt;/a&gt; idea didn’t win either but was accepted into RevTech’s 2.0 class and did recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://detailedblock.com/2013/12/12/katie-levans-gives-advice-entrepreneurs/&quot;&gt;win a prize&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Startup Weekend is to simulate the process of going through a startup. You do not have to have a team already assembled. In fact it’s discouraged. Startup Weekend is about encouraging new business ideas &amp;#x26; innovation so you shouldn’t be walking in with a fully laid out business plan. For the other participants some of the joy is getting to work with people you may “know of” in the CLT startup community but haven’t actually had a chance to work with previously/professionally. The creative/collaborative energy of the team is one of the best experiences to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pitching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrive early-ish before 6pm. The food is quite good, last year it was Pure Pizza from 7th St Public Market. There are always vegetarian options (but not necessarily vegan or gluten free, unless you request them). When you arrive and register you’ll be given a color coded name tag. The colors change from year to year but each color associates to a developer, a designer and non-technical. Learn those color assignments because that will help you target who you want/need to talk to as you work the room before pitches start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you talk to people and identify their skills ask why they’re there. Some enjoy the creative process/want to try new skills, some want to be part of a company that will make a real go of it, others want their own pitch to get picked. Absolutely connect with the designers, because your team will really struggle without one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason to work the room beforehand is that everybody with an idea pitches. Once pitches are done, everyone votes and the 6 or so pitches/ideas that received the most votes are picked as that weekend’s startups. Everyone should then go work on one of those 6 ideas. So the reason to work the room early is twofold, identify those with the skills you need for your team and to also solicit votes for your pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXeAUq891rU&amp;#x26;list=PL1E88D9A00D73F7ED&amp;#x26;index=1&quot;&gt;last year’s pitches&lt;/a&gt; and compare those to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte.startupweekend.org/category/meat-the-teams/&quot;&gt;companies that were selected&lt;/a&gt;. During the pitch what will attract people is a genuinely interesting problem and a UNIQUE way of tackling it. Do not forget to say in your pitch the roles/talents your team needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once on a team you want to keep your focus on what is known as the minimum viable product (MVP). That is the product or process with the fewest number of features that demonstrate what the company does so that users can accomplish their goal. Having at least one graphic designer can help so that the user interface is well designed and enjoyable. If you have a second designer, creating mockups for the development team or the presentation for the judges can be a real strategic asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Presenting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judges that participate in CSW are from the Charlotte community who’ve created and sold their own startups. What they want to see in Sunday’s pitch is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Validation of the Product&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure out if people are interested in your product as quickly as possible. Previous teams targeting products for the restaurant industry have gone out on Friday nights to talk to bar managers and customers. Don’t forget your fellow CSW participants, you can survey them. If you talk to potential customers and no one is eager for the solution, come up with a new idea! This happens a lot even into Saturday. Part of your team should make a website, a twitter account &amp;#x26; a Facebook page for the company and fill them with marketing copy. Use all the free CSW goodies like .co domains, launchrock templates, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Addressable Market&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venture capitalists that typically are the judges like to see a 10x return on their investment. Let’s say your idea gets picked on Friday. At your presentation on Sunday when you go through what problem the company is trying to solve and how the solution does that there should be a part where you ask for X amount of money to start the company. For instance let’s say you ask for &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;&lt;math&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;&lt;mrow&gt;&lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mo separator=&quot;true&quot;&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mn&gt;000.&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;annotation encoding=&quot;application/x-tex&quot;&gt;100,000. So the judges will want to see that theoretically the company could earn at least&lt;/annotation&gt;&lt;/semantics&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;strut&quot; style=&quot;height:0.8888799999999999em;vertical-align:-0.19444em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mpunct&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mspace&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.16666666666666666em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.05764em;&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.05724em;&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;u&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.03588em;&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02691em;&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02691em;&quot;&gt;w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.03588em;&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.03588em;&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;u&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;1,000,000 per yr. Let’s say the amount of money for your market is &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;&lt;math&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;&lt;mrow&gt;&lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;.&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;annotation encoding=&quot;application/x-tex&quot;&gt;1 billion. The cliche phrase is to get 1% of the&lt;/annotation&gt;&lt;/semantics&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;strut&quot; style=&quot;height:0.8888799999999999em;vertical-align:-0.19444em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.13889em;&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.03588em;&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;1 billion spent per year to use your app. The app’s income would be &lt;span class=&quot;katex&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-mathml&quot;&gt;&lt;math&gt;&lt;semantics&gt;&lt;mrow&gt;&lt;mn&gt;10&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;.&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;Y&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;annotation encoding=&quot;application/x-tex&quot;&gt;10 million. Your addressable market is&lt;/annotation&gt;&lt;/semantics&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;katex-html&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;base&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;strut&quot; style=&quot;height:0.69444em;vertical-align:0em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.22222em;&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;u&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.01968em;&quot;&gt;l&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.02778em;&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:0.03148em;&quot;&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mord mathdefault&quot;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;1 billion, the return on investment is 99%. All of this is fake but it demonstrates the type of numbers &amp;#x26; terminology the judges want to see used. Someone in the team will need to google the industry numbers and figure out the addressable market/ROI. If your addressable market is too small change the business model or the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Business Plan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonprofit doesn’t mean it has to lose money. Making money is a means of being sustainable and only a signal that what the company does provides value that customers want. Look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kiva.org&quot;&gt;http://www.kiva.org&lt;/a&gt; it has a social mission &amp;#x26; investors are paid a return for their risk. Discuss why your product or business model is better than your competitors. If your product has no competitors you may be chasing a market no one wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup Weekend can be a tremendously rewarding experience when you are open to change. Your pitch may not be picked; join one of the selected teams who have an idea that is particularly challenging or who have members you don’t know. Your professional expertise may not be used; learn about an industry/vertical new to you or try new skills by filling in a missing role on your team. Most of all collaborate with your team members, you’re there to help each other build the best product &amp;#x26; presentation. Like life, you’ll get out of Charlotte Startup Weekend what you put into it. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spreading Happiness (happygifs.co) Faster]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vegan hotdogs lead to increased performance. Believe me or not, but it’s true. The actual story was Joshua Mauldin, maker of iOS apps…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/spreading-happiness-faster/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/spreading-happiness-faster/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Vegan hotdogs lead to increased performance. Believe me or not, but it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual story was &lt;a href=&quot;https://joshuamauldin.com/&quot;&gt;Joshua Mauldin&lt;/a&gt;, maker of iOS apps, websites and a lover of design and I caught up at JJ Red Hot&apos;s for lunch. He created BlendConf&apos;s excellent t-shirt swag thru his &lt;a href=&quot;https://neuedist.com/&quot;&gt;Neuedist&lt;/a&gt; project. He told me his new playground is &lt;a href=&quot;https://happygifs.co/&quot;&gt;happygifs.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website serves a happiness-inspiring animated gif. Who doesn&apos;t want to share or show their happiness around the holidays? If the first load doesn&apos;t please you Scrooge McDuck, hit &quot;Get Happier&quot; and try again. Joshua and I talked of our mutual obsession with page speed and that it wasn&apos;t as fast as he would like. Let&apos;s see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the performance of the website, we want to take measurements as close as possible to the server. This is a quick test, so we&apos;ll do our best. Geographic distance typically leads to more network hops. More hops mean a slower experience for that user, so let&apos;s find where happygifs.co lives:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;traceroute www.happygifs.co&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;shows the site hosted with DigitalOcean, whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/questions/datacenters-where-are-these-located-is-there-a-plan-for-the-data-center-in-asia-singapore&quot;&gt;datacenter is in New York&lt;/a&gt;. Of the webpagetest.org testing locations, Virginia is the closest. Here&apos;s the median of a 5 test run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Load Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;First Byte&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Start Render&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/webpagetest.org/docs/using-webpagetest/metrics/speed-index&quot;&gt;Speed Index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;First View&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;3.692s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;0.164s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;0.590s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;898&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;3.692s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Repeat View&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2.127s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;0.125s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;0.303s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;540&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;2.127s&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the detailed results linked below, you&apos;ll see all the tests ran using Chrome on Cable modem speed. How did I decide to use Chrome? By consulting &lt;a href=&quot;https://gs.statcounter.com/#desktop+mobile+tablet-browser_version-na-quarterly-201304-201304-bar&quot;&gt;the most popular browsers this quarter by Version &amp;#x26; Platform for North America&lt;/a&gt;. Other is a combination of everything else and it likely had such a large share since I requested stats including mobile. Chrome did not have the largest individual share but combined its share was larger than IE&apos;s. Not every browser is available in every location so sometimes it&apos;s difficult to get consistent analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;When&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data seems to behave as you would expect. A repeated view is faster than the first view because the browser should be caching page elements. Yet, the devil is in the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webpagetest.org/result/131218_JH_V8E/&quot;&gt;individual results in the 5 test run&lt;/a&gt;. In the screenshots, you&apos;ll see a different featured image on each request. Thus the runs were all first views. You should notice there&apos;s a high degree of variability in the results. The average is masking the range in page load from 1.688 to 9.178 seconds. As you look at the waterfall diagrams you should notice that the variability is happening for 2 different reasons. Either the gif is the slowest page element or the advertisements are. Unfortunately, the third-party APIs and ad delivery networks are out of Joshua&apos;s control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole time we&apos;ve been in the weeds, let&apos;s now look at those large colored letter grades at the top. Greenlit A&apos;s all around for &lt;em&gt;Time to First Byte&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Keep-Alive Enabled&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Compress Transfer&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Compress Images&lt;/em&gt; is not applicable so there&apos;s no rating, &lt;em&gt;Effective use of CDN&lt;/em&gt; is an X and there&apos;s an F for &lt;em&gt;Cache static content&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://toolbar.netcraft.com/site_report?url=happygifs.co#last_reboot&quot;&gt;quick query of Netcraft&lt;/a&gt; tells us the site is running Nginx 1.2.1 so we know what web server directives to use. TTF is text so we can compress it. Add the following to &lt;em&gt;/etc/nginx/nginx.conf&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;gzip_types&lt;/em&gt; to cover the webf onts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;font/opentype font/truetype application/x-font-ttf application/vnd.ms-fontobject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web server should have the correct MIME type to deliver the custom webfonts. Add to &lt;em&gt;/etc/nginx/mime.types&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;font/opentype                 ott;
application/font-woff         woff;
application/x-font-ttf        ttf;
application/vnd.ms-fontobject eot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fonts served and compressed, now we tell browsers to cache all the static assets. Add these  settings like above to mime.types. They are not the most aggressive, instead, caching for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;location ~* \.(css|eot|gif|ico|jpg|jpeg|jpe|js|png|svg|svgz|tif|tiff|ttf|woff)$ {
    expires 2592000s;
    add_header Pragma public;
    add_header Cache-Control &amp;quot;public, must-revalidate, proxy-revalidate&amp;quot;;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there are a few page elements that we may be able to offload from Joshua&apos;s site. We can look up if the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdnjs.com/&quot;&gt;css and javascript libraries are available on a CDN&lt;/a&gt;. Bootstrap may not be applicable if he&apos;s customized it. Here are the URLs to use in his link directives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/animate.css/3.1.0/animate.min.css
//netdna.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/3.1.1/css/bootstrap.min.css
//netdna.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/3.1.1/js/bootstrap.min.js
//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/fastclick/1.0.0/fastclick.min.js
//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery-cookie/1.4.1/jquery.cookie.min.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the application to store the gifs in Amazon&apos;s S3/Cloudfront or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdnplanet.com/cdns/&quot;&gt;competitor&lt;/a&gt; CDN could be the next step. With the logs from the site, we could forecast his costs to help pick a service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Who&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beneficiary is everyone. Faster websites make us all happy even when the content isn&apos;t animated gifs of adorable kittens frockling. A better user experience is what Google rewards in their search results. If you&apos;re a website owner it is in your best interest to care about speed.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Parallels of DevOps & Yoga]]></title><description><![CDATA[I had a job that made me unhappy until one day I quit. No plan, no interviews scheduled, no idea what I desired to work on next, not even…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/parallels-devops-yoga/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/parallels-devops-yoga/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had a job that made me unhappy until one day I quit. No plan, no interviews scheduled, no idea what I desired to work on next, not even sure if I wanted to stay in technology I was so burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the summer off, dropped 5% of my body fat, put on 15 lbs of muscle, my workouts were my only schedule. I&apos;d been practicing yoga for a couple of years as a complement and recovery to my athletic endeavours. But this period seemed the right time to take yoga teacher training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those nine months of training our class had lots of discussions. In one a fellow trainee described an article he read on the frequency of practicing yoga and its benefits. The central idea was that doing something more often made you better at it faster and cited a study of Korean War fighter pilots. I stopped listening to my classmate as the bomb went off in my head that he had described to class the OODA loop (Orient, Observe, Decide &amp;#x26; Act).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Boyd&apos;s OODA loop is one of the founding ideas behind release early &amp;#x26; often philosophy. This ideology grew into Agile Development in software development and Lean Startup in business. Where does does DevOps come into play with yoga?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a quick rehash. DevOps is the merging of the business and the development process. As software changes from a packaged product at a store to an online service, software development is evolving. Business development or product managers used to decide what to build. They then told the developers who handed the code to system administrators to deploy to servers. Now customers dictate features. The faster a company finds those customers and responds to their needs the faster it has a sustainable product. What does any of that have to do with yoga? My axiom is that yoga &amp;#x26; devops have the same goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Union&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of work by scholars of Eastern and Western backgrounds about what is yoga the union of and its philosophy. I am not going to summarize those arguments. Let me go with the assumption that most Americans experience yoga as exercise. While yoga can be a great workout many people I know who who go appreciate getting out of their head. The mental noise of the day quiets as the sense of the body being the vessel of the mind blurs. It&apos;s a feeling of connection. We are so much more than the sum of our parts, whether it is our intellect, our corporal selves or as individuals. When someone knows that from within they can be so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is this same blurring we desire out of DevOps. Developers that understand the servers they&apos;re designing and deploying applications onto. Systems administrators that are writing code to respond to customer demands. Sometimes in a yoga class when we feel the most taxed the mind starts talking to the tiny voices that are our heart. These conversations that break down the us versus them dynamic of an IT team are huge. Teams that connect, speak the same language of code, and serve customers can be so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Knowing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be a lifeguard. When you are drowning, breathing is both the goal and hard to do. Starting a yoga practice can feel the same. The teacher may be saying inhale and exhale but you&apos;re just trying to keep up. Some poses you&apos;ll love because it allows you to catch your breath. In time, you&apos;ll notice the poses where you hold your breath. Maybe you figure out not breathing makes those poses more difficult. Maybe you notice how you don&apos;t breathe sitting in traffic or during important meetings. Maybe you inhale. How&apos;s your day going? Check your breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I heard of the Monitorama conference it had sold out. Monitoring is awesome. I understand some hate monitoring because monitoring means an alert of an emergency and something has to be fixed. Some may love graphs, I love the answers monitoring provides. It tells me if server capacity can be reduced to save money or does this code need to be refactored because it takes too long to run. Are customers using the new features that were rolled out? How&apos;s the business doing? Check your monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agility&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have any of your friends said &quot;I can&apos;t do yoga, I&apos;m not flexibile&quot;? Mine have. For whatever reason people sometimes define themselves by what they don&apos;t do. The beauty of language is the nuance and subtlety between words. In common practice we may think of agility as the same as being flexible. Your friend may not be flexible in this moment but that is not a permanent state. Regular yoga can improve flexibility. The greater benefit of practice may be increased agility, the ability to move without thought. Getting out of the head, feeling a connected self that does not labor on reasons not to act that&apos;s being agile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical people are fun. We like debating nuance and subtlety at times. There is Agile with a capital letter a implying one of the formal agile processes. There is agile with a lower case that is squishier, less structured. It incorporates what is needed without the rigidity that does not fit the situation. DevOps takes neither side with it&apos;s ship it philosophy. Is a production system broken? Fix it so it doesn&apos;t happen again and get better. Ship, learn, iterate that&apos;s agile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Perfection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our American culture focuses on perfection. People often feel their yoga poses have to be perfect. They love the poses that are easy to them, hate the ones they struggle with. Yet American&apos;s embrace of failure has led it to be an economic powerhouse. The US&apos;s bankruptcy laws encourage trying new business ventures. When they don&apos;t work out, all parties move on. You see this in venture capitalists that ask what founders learned from their ventures that fold. Tell someone what you&apos;ve learned from poses you disliked than show off a pose that&apos;s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about DevOps is its ship it philosophy. Combined with monitoring the team learns far more, faster, and they become more agile. It is a practice that reinforces itself. Rather than hold back a new feature for an application for the usual delays, ship the smallest piece. See what the team learns. Often you&apos;ll find people want the features they need than the feature that&apos;s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Breaking Habits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we feel connected, and we know how we feel because we know how we&apos;re breathing, we can be decisive. Rather than hung up on feeling what we must do or can not do, we do. The OODA loop of observe, orient, decide, act is what my classmate was touching on that day. The faster and more times we go through this loop the more negative thoughts or feelings we get out of ourselves. Once those are out, space opens for what can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a teacher that before showing how to get into any new pose she would show how to fall out of it. We would see there wasn&apos;t far to fall. Sure we still struggled in it the first time but I didn&apos;t fall. The second time through I knew what to do and fell pretty quick. The third time I knew where failure happened and corrected for it. Then keeping my breath, not overthinking nor worrying to make it perfect, held the pose. OODA loop in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is your organization in incorporating DevOps? Do siloed development and operations teams now collaborate at the start of new projects? Maybe they swap code as projects evolve. The technical team and business team are sharing data to improve product or processes. New insights get released to customers to test. Many will say DevOps is the lastest IT fad. Others many counter it doesn&apos;t work in the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time through a process is uncomfortable. The set up of the tooling can feel burdensome. If you don&apos;t go through a process first you cannot incorporate the lessons into the second time. You&apos;ll see the process didn&apos;t take as long. Perhaps the third time through there is a change and it&apos;s handled fast. OODA loop in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yoga and DevOps are used in different environments but their outcomes and goals are similar. The lessons of one can be carried into the other. If you&apos;re a developer sitting at a desk go take a yoga class. Did being in class feel like your software development or deploy process ? If you&apos;re a yoga practitioner and now you&apos;re curious about writing code, leave a comment and I&apos;ll show how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Claire Danes Taught Me about DevOps]]></title><description><![CDATA[In July my voice teacher let me know that Homeland was looking for yoga practitioners for a scene. Between the morning when she mentioned it…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/what-claire-danes-taught-me-about-devops/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/what-claire-danes-taught-me-about-devops/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In July my voice teacher let me know that Homeland was looking for yoga practitioners for a scene. Between the morning when she mentioned it and the afternoon when she filled me in on the details to apply, seemingly twitter, facebook and even lunch time TV news had spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I first intended to try out as a lark now seemed daunting. With a little encouragement from my teacher, I applied, and was cast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning I showed up on set I was promoted from extra to stand-in because I resembled one of the actors. As a stand-in, you&apos;re on set to watch as the actors rehearse the scene, the actors &amp;#x26; directors discussing blocking (where they&apos;ll stand &amp;#x26; move across the set), then (surprise!) stand-in for the principal actor while lighting and sound make their adjustments for shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actors come back, you as stand-in get out of the way, and the crew shoots the scene. There isn&apos;t much to do, so it affords a lot of time to observe. That&apos;s how I noticed the production of a television episode is a lot like software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A television episode is like your web application in that the episode is a collection of scenes like features that seek to provide value. In the case of the episode the end value is entertainment. As a television series seeks an audience the success of a software product is determined by serving a user base. Each scene of an episode can be defined as a code sprint, as each scene moves a narrative forward the goal of a sprint is a well defined result such as particular features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think of DevOps what comes to mind? For me the primary tenants are a culture of operations, development and business communicating. One also monitors everything, use the information to get better and adopt code as infrastructure so processes are repeatable, testable and move toward continuous deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How a television episode is made is more about their process and their people and this is the core message of the devops movement. Television shows have ratings to monitor their interaction with their audience hopefully you have monitoring not just for your infrastructure but every business aspect that&apos;s critical to your application&apos;s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one afternoon I saw tape marked onto a floor to note where an actor would stand for their next shot, chrome trim of cars sprayed with a matte film to prevent distracting reflections, and entire system of fake licenses plates depending on desired location &amp;#x26; context (i.e.: principal characters, multiple federal agencies, general local MD/DC/VA license plates) just as any web application from the infrastructure code to front end assets are going to have hundreds of details to track or change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a stand-in I was literally a mock object for camera angles &amp;#x26; lightening adjustments to be set. Sounds a lot like writing test driven development doesn&apos;t ? Once your test cases are set up and you&apos;re creating the actual features, we know writing software doesn&apos;t always go right the first time. The same happens to actors, sometimes they flub the scene and break the build so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers we iterate until our features pass. When there are multiple bad takes I saw no one on set crucify who made the mistake; I think it&apos;s important part of DevOps culture that instead of finger pointing the issue is addressed and everyone goes on. Another aspect of filming is that their process is repeatable, capturing another take on a scene is not considered a failure. Sometimes the crew kick off another build by reshooting the scene just so to make sure they got it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure my metaphor may break down in that film &amp;#x26; tv production is incredibly manual in the numbers of people that are employed where software teams following agile processes can be be incredibly small. But hear me out. If we take scenes within an episode as equivalent to our code sprint, then easily we can draw the Director as product owner who is executing on the episode or product vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the episode/web application is the end product how does everyone else fit? Without writers creating a script, or designers &amp;#x26; front end engineers there&apos;s nothing with which for the audience or users to interact. Where do actors and developers come in? They are the creators shaping the execution, using their creativity to give life to that episode or product. If an actor without a stage is just two people mumbling at each other, code without deployment are bits on a hard drive. Sound, lights, camera crew are the specialists of networking, security, and infrastructure in deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no wall of that&apos;s acting &amp;#x26; that&apos;s production just as DevOps embraces as we&apos;ve moved from shipped stand alone software to continuously deployed web applications. Wardrobe and props are functions that help actors best embody their character just as building internal environments of development &amp;#x26; staging or the quality assurance teams help the team create their best product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 1200px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/0f98f/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAGAAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECAwX/xAAWAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAL/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAAejKWWzIL//EABgQAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQIh/9oACAEBAAEFAujbM6cpSn//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAEDAQE/AT//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAECAQE/AT//xAAUEAEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAg/9oACAEBAAY/Al//xAAaEAEAAwADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhUbHw/9oACAEBAAE/IRsusGZvEVruYUY1qeVP/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBjL//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAR/9oACAEDAQE/EEf/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAgEBPxBX/8QAGxABAQEAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBYZH/2gAIAQEAAT8QqgHhEDLWkvZCYuqNwqAP3QU3nScQPXTf/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Homeland Season 3 Episode 5 The Yoga Play Script&quot;
        title=&quot;Homeland Season 3 Episode 5 The Yoga Play Script&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/e5166/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/f93b5/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg 300w,
/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/b4294/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg 600w,
/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/e5166/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg 1200w,
/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/d9c39/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg 1800w,
/static/17f4811e6ed0c5bfbe2cbdee59e263a8/0f98f/homeland-S03-E05-the-yoga-play-script.jpg 1920w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an extra waiting to see if you were cut from a scene feels a bit like waiting to see if your pull request gets accepted into a major open source project. With this past Sunday&apos;s airing of Episode 5, I was able to capture a screenshot of me in the green shirt straightening up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.8thstreetstudio.com&quot;&gt;8th Street Studio&lt;/a&gt; as the actor I stood in for left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I learn about DevOps spending the day alternating between 2 feet and 20 feet from Claire Danes? That to win an Emmy and put out a great episode/product you need a testable, repeatable process and a talented team around you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blend Conference 2013]]></title><description><![CDATA[They say the right thing happens at the right time. I had the pleasure of working with Bermon Painter while he was organizing this event…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/blend-conference-2013/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/blend-conference-2013/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;They say the right thing happens at the right time. I had the pleasure of working with Bermon Painter while he was organizing this event. What attracted me was an interactive driven environment and a multidisciplinary schedule. The notebook handed out to all attendees became full. I’ll do my best to summarize the experience and the longest lasting take aways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Workshop Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Think Like a Startup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was everything you learn at Startup Weekend compressed into 2 hours and with a twist. Each person listed their own values and those were pooled to create group values. If I had not taken my sabbatical I could not have expressed those values I bring to my work and client projects. With an engineer&apos;s mindset, I did struggle with the undefined nature of the product creation. Thru the experience I found creating a product from place of heart is powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Service Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had heard never heard the term before paying attention to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ptquattlebaum.tumblr.com/post/60645307036/service-design-making-blend-conference&quot;&gt;Patrick’s Quatttlebaum’s slides&lt;/a&gt;. It examines operations, culture &amp;#x26; organization for impacts on the customer&apos;s experience. Uber (that secretly launched in Charlotte during the conference) was an example. They looked at the taxi/hired car experience. Uber examined what do customers want, what do employees want, what are the operations that need to be in place to please both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;VIP Dinner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening set the tone for the conference conversations I had later. This was going to be the kind of conference many attendees would write up. I found myself wondering how to have something unique thing to write. Asking my table companions what they had been reading was the theme I hit upon for everyone I spoke to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing my notes of the talks I scribbled down was a lot of practical advice. Sometimes conferences can have a lot of inspiration and not a lot of application. Here the useful chunks here sprinkled like breadcrumbs along the trail. I learned a lot from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ashedryden.com/blend-conf-keynote-programming-diversity&quot;&gt;Ashe Dryden’s session Programming Diversity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took no notes during Carl Smith’s talk because he&apos;s such a great speaker. Just let him tell you about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bs0OcvwgpGk&quot;&gt;Your Money or Your Life&lt;/a&gt;. The video isn&apos;t from BlendConf but it&apos;s the same talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&apos;s my favorite client, hands down. How often do you get emails that are all caps that say MORE FUCKING LIGHTNING?&quot; James White&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post title comes from James White&apos;s talk about being a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXul0Xojci0&quot;&gt;Design Renegade&lt;/a&gt;. I was able to find it from another conference. The relevant story starts at the 41:38 mark. As a developer I would say it is more diffult to apply his lessons, but he’s inspiring and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Become a Better Designer with Side Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create content with personality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put in the work. Side projects show yourself that you want to be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/ttimsmith/become-a-better-designer-with-side-projects-blend-conf&quot;&gt;Slides for Become a Better Designer with Side Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Convincing Clients Without (Much) Bravado&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant Seeds for what is best&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prescriptive Feedback “sounds like the problem you’re trying to solve is…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give 2 Options You Can Live With&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hybrids Rule Everything Around Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop being the roadblock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Just Ship It”, it’s not easy but necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/bryan/hybrids-rule-everything-around-me-blendconf&quot;&gt;Slides for Hybrids Rule Everything Around Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Nuances of UX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aim for design that doesn&apos;t get noticed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design problems stick out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features &amp;#x26; version numbers don&apos;t improve the experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sell the experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crow in Your First Yoga Class]]></title><description><![CDATA[I believe I am like most men in that my practice started with a girlfriend. One that took me to my first yoga class, where I muddled through…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/crow-your-first-yoga-class/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/crow-your-first-yoga-class/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I believe I am like most men in that my practice started with a girlfriend. One that took me to my first yoga class, where I muddled through my first poses, and yet I found a way into bakasana, crow pose. Let me tell you how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met at a mutual friend’s wedding. She had just returned from saving sea turtles in Central America. I was into competitive cycling at the time but she still owned more bicycles than me. It’s reasons like those that I found myself at a yoga studio in Denver, CO in 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I thought of yoga as some kind of stretching. So going to a class sounded like a great idea after hiking &amp;#x26; skiing. All I thought to ask her was what to wear. Luckily I brought some long loose shorts for hiking and a wicking t-shirt. I had no idea of the types of studios or styles of yoga practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived late, but before class started; I grabbed a rental mat and headed into the studio. There were no open spaces together. I took the slot near the front so she could have the one in the back. I don’t remember the instructor, I don’t remember if there was heart speech or we meditated at the beginning. I don’t remember the music. I remember the heat. Now that I know more about yoga, I know I wasn’t in a certified bikram studio. Whatever you have planned in your day do your body a favor, go drink a glass of water right now. I’ll wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was tasty huh? Back to the moments in class. I was sweating. We were only sitting. When class started I did the best that I could. I already had trouble remembering left from right, adding upside down didn’t help. I looked at the teacher and the other students a lot. I had no idea what some of the words I heard were but I could mime along with whatever everyone else was doing. I held my breath as I moved, I got tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we found ourselves squatting on our mats. The teacher said something like roll our weight onto our palms, let our shins find our arms and lift our toes. So I did. It wasn’t beautiful, not at all. My elbows were dug into the pocket of my knees. I did not stay in the pose a long time. Yet, my girlfriend later remarked she was impressed to see me do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t understand because I had been able to do that all along. How bones stack and my balancing point was something I had found through play. I had not had any exposure to yoga before. What I did have was a lot of time in deep left field as a horrible t-ball player. As a child I was not skilled nor were the teams we played against. There was not a lot to do in the outfield. I kicked all the anthills. Sometimes I sat. Sometimes I tried to balance on my arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost 20 years after playing I found a use for that skill. It just happened to be in a yoga class. My point is not to forget to play. It’s important not because of what play teaches you now but because of what you learn from play in the future. This is what’s beautiful about devops and yoga, the encouragement to try new things whether it is a pose or a deployment process. Failure occurs when we continue with what we know does not work. Do something disparate from your routine. Just play.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SearchExchange 2013]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm always interested in fields parallel to my own. When Experience Farm offered me their tickets to a digital marketing conference I hopped…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/searchexchange-2013/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/searchexchange-2013/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m always interested in fields parallel to my own. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://experiencefarm.com&quot;&gt;Experience Farm&lt;/a&gt; offered me their tickets to a digital marketing conference I hopped right on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SearchExchange 2013 had three tracks: Pay Per Click (PPC), Search Engine Optimization (SEO), and Social Media Marketing (SMM). As a freelance developer in Charlotte these are areas that I have to pay attention to for clients. But it&apos;s fun to get deep into a speciality from the general of my day to day. I appreciated the focus this conference kept by having the individual tracks as separate days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day One, Pay-Per-Click&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first day of the conference I had to miss the morning sessions. The great thing about conferences is often that someone else is also taking notes. Here&apos;s a summary of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blueion.com/blog/search-exchange-day-1-pay-per-click-advertising/&quot;&gt;Search Exchange Day 1 Pay Per Click Advertising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides from the presenters I could find were Justin Vanning from SEOmoz speaking on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/JustinVanning/ppc-is-not-enough-how-i-learned-to-embrace-holistic-growth-marketing-at-moz-and-tips-to-help-you-do-the-same&quot;&gt;PPC is not Enough. How I Learned to Embrace Holistic Growth Marketing at Moz and Tips to Help You Do the Same&lt;/a&gt; and Kayla Kurtz of Hanapin whose keynote was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/hanapinmarketing/a-ppc-odyssey-kayla-kurtz-at-search-exchange-keynote&quot;&gt;2015: A PPC Odyssey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day Two, Search Engine Optimization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockfish Interactive&apos;s Steve Plunkett started the morning with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/djpaisley/steveplunkett-4-cs-seo-keynote-searchexchange-searchex&quot;&gt;The 4 C&apos;s Classification, Customers, Clarity, Content&lt;/a&gt;. Afterward Joe Hall from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetmarketingninjas.com/&quot;&gt;Internet Marketing Ninjas&lt;/a&gt; spoke on Identifying Patterns. Virante&apos;s Phil Buckley closed with SEO without Keywords, The Future is Now. The two sessions that stood out for me were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Local Search Works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Ballantyne Explains How Local Search Works&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bland title but the content made up for it. Local search propagates from 5 key sources thru &lt;a href=&quot;http://getlisted.org&quot;&gt;http://getlisted.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As search engines are machines they like to see consistency. They reward finding the same information wherever they find you. Thomas coined a phrase Consistant NAPS Rock. By NAPS he doesn&apos;t mean sleeping for an hour in the afternoon. NAPS are Names, Address, Phone number, and Site. Name should be the business name. Address is the physical address of the business not a post office box. Consistency in this information is key he said. Phone numbers should include the area code and be a local number. They are trust signal. Thomas warned not to use a tracking phone number such as a service from the Yellow Pages. When the business stops paying for that tracking number all the SEO value earned goes with it. Reviews are valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas also touched on how encrypted search isn&apos;t passing on search terms. The useless &quot;not provided&quot; in Google Analytics reports. For &quot;Bars in Charlotte&quot;, that means carousel results are rewritten. When a user clicks a choice, again a results page displays. Those links then lead to the landing page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a marketer when you can&apos;t make a decision, throw the data out. Google Web Trends is muddy data. The best advice was from &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchengineland.com/turning-not-provided-into-useful-actionable-data-135800&quot;&gt;How To Turn (Not Provided) Into Useful, Actionable Data&lt;/a&gt;. Year after year data is quite different, explain that as early as possible in a client relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Moneyball Your SEO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Ferguson presented this fun titled talk where &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.fangdigital.com/seo-moneyball?utm_campaign=SEO&amp;#x26;utm_content=SEOMoneyballeBook&amp;#x26;utm_medium=Trade+Show&amp;#x26;utm_source=Trade+Show+-+Search+Exchange&quot;&gt;more depth is available in this ebook&lt;/a&gt;. His recommendation was to use the people on your staff to create the sum role of SEO specialists. Here are the parts that were relevant to me as freelance developer in Charlotte. For instance the SEO function of site architecture. Typical responsibilities are HTML best practices, tag authorship, and navigation. Page load speed and W3C compliance fall into that role too. Of course those are tasks for software engineers or developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tool he recommended for analysis was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/&quot;&gt;Screaming Frog&apos;s SEO Spider&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day Three, Social Media Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic was one that interested me as many friends work in various aspects of social media marketing. Some as content producers, strategists or educating clients to manage their own message. Kevin Briody presented &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paceco.com/social-content-engines-notes-from-search-exchange-2013/&quot;&gt;Creating Your Social Content Engine&lt;/a&gt; Then Brian Chappell talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://adaptpartners.com/designing-big-content-presentation/&quot;&gt;Designing Big Content&lt;/a&gt;. Again two sessions grabbed me for different reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social Media Advertising Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marty Weintraub from aimClear presented about his efforts from Forbes on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2013/05/01/how-to-triple-your-success-using-social-media-advertising-platforms/&quot;&gt;click per action&lt;/a&gt;. He also covered the resulting SEO benefits from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aimclearblog.com/2013/05/20/why-seo-link-builders-are-dead-without-paid-organic-social-content-distribution/&quot;&gt;Why SEO Link Builders are Dead without Paid Organic Social Content Distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Media exists to drive Conversions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your social media is not driving share you&apos;re either creating content for your existing market or no one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search PPC extends organic, social should be using paid content extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possible to spend money on content strategy &amp;#x26; community and achieve nothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn did the W thing i.e.: &apos;whore&apos;, sells more ad space now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bid Twitter &amp;#x26; LinkedIn ads 20-30% lower than budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Until you get the impressions wanted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nickel up from there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For tight psychographics, send visitor to an informational page &amp;#x26; an opt in form&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The phrase Learn More had a high conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aimclearblog.com/2013/01/09/inbound-pr-pulling-media-mindshare-with-content-big-data/&quot;&gt;Targeting Journalists in Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective use of paid social booster, can create the organic social effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First party interest blogger can set retargeting cookies that they could resell to the 3rd party that wants to know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal page promotion can only aim ads at your own fans, but you can reach friends of friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How I Made Over Half a Million Dollars Wasting Time on Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neal Rodriguez was an excellent speaker to close out a conference. The hint that it would was at lunch when I overheard an unusual conversation amongst the presenters. When they asked me &quot;Am I in?&quot; they explained how his presentation would be interactive. Neal as a speaker is charisimatic, energetic and informative. He also swears, &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. So the speakers had a cooler, a couple cases of beer and passed them out before Neal started. The rules were simple drink every time he said fuck. In the fifty minute presentation, I drank almost three Natty Light&apos;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist of what he presented sans the explicit language can be found in the piece he wrote last year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/nealrodriguez/2012/07/03/social-media-time-suck/&quot;&gt;Why I Waste Time on Social Media&lt;/a&gt;. Neal identifies cultural trends, creates content utilizing them. Then using key relationships he develops to target specific audiences seeds that content. The key points were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotting Trends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://socialblade.com/&quot;&gt;SocialBlade&lt;/a&gt; gives stats for top channels in a youtube category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/keyword_tool&quot;&gt;Youtube&apos;s Keyword Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/trends/&quot;&gt;Google Trends&lt;/a&gt; to get ideas of what events people are looking for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find targets of blogs to build guest blogger relationships&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.similarsites.com/&quot;&gt;SimilarSites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/blogsearch&quot;&gt;Google Blog Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.problogger.net/&quot;&gt;ProBlogger.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each potential partner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read 5-10 articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the comments to see what that community wants to consume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a worthwhile conference. I had a chance to catch up with friends from the Charlotte social media community. Most important I learned more how my role as a developer goes hand in hand with theirs as marketers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Perfect is Less than Done]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you don't know "Done is Better than Perfect" is a quote from Mark Zuckerberg and over the past year I've come to understand it more than…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/perfect-less-than-done/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/perfect-less-than-done/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you don&apos;t know &quot;Done is Better than Perfect&quot; is a quote from Mark Zuckerberg and over the past year I&apos;ve come to understand it more than its surface expression. 99.99% as much as possible uptime. All the security patches in place. Waterfall driven development of politically based features. An environment that conditioned perfection and guaranteed failure. I took a break, did some exploration and came up with what will be here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not the first persona to write about yoga nor cutting edge technology and software development. It&apos;s occurred to me how much they fit together so I&apos;m writing about both; Thus the blog tagline &quot;finding flexibility in software and the body&quot;. Maybe some software developers will take up a practice where I&apos;ve had my best ideas. The best outcome might be if casual yogis become developers. Primarily I&apos;ll be writing topics within software development specifically DevOps during the week and on weekends will be lighter fare about the parallels between yoga and DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve sat on the idea of this site for a couple months as I finished up teacher training. I was stuck on lots of ideas of my own making. I hadn&apos;t written the puppet scripts for my own server, the site didn&apos;t load up in sub 4 seconds, the theme I&apos;m using is off the shelf, am I adding anything unique. I frustrated myself not because they weren&apos;t things I didn&apos;t know, but because precisely I knew how to do them and thus believed these were things on which I would be judged. To be honest when I read a blog I run performance analysis on it. But I had to let that go for myself. This is my lab not a gallery.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Five Lessons from My First Yoga Teacher]]></title><description><![CDATA[Last weekend my first yoga teacher got married. While at the wedding I thought about how we met when I started practicing 8 years ago. That…]]></description><link>https://www.scottelundgren.com/five-lessons-first-yoga-teacher/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scottelundgren.com/five-lessons-first-yoga-teacher/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend my first yoga teacher got married. While at the wedding I thought about how we met when I started practicing 8 years ago. That reminded me about when I was in yoga teacher training earlier this year. My fellow yoga teacher trainees and I discussed our perceptions of yoga we had as beginning students.  As the ceremony started, I thought about the lessons that teacher taught me that helped avoid the early problems they felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first regular yoga classes were at a bike shop. Around 10 guys aged 19 to 30 would meet for a group ride from the shop near Uptown. Our fearless ride leader, a former mountain bike racer and yoga teacher would then lead a sequence afterward. From her we all learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. No One Wins a Trophy at Yoga&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be hard pressed to find a more competitive bunch than 20 &amp;#x26; 30something cyclists. The strongest athlete is able to outlast their competitors. Sensing how strong your fellow riders feel can be an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so on a yoga mat. Maybe you take a quick glance around the room to ensure you’ve followed directions right. Looking to see if one could go deeper into a pose than say Mike resulted in tough love. I don’t know how many times we fell into each other as she lead us thru poses with our eyes closed to get us to focus on ourselves than each other. The lesson was all that mattered was on our own mat. As we each bought our own mat, she started bringing kids stickers. During savasana she&apos;d place a sticker on the corner. There are no trophies in yoga, but sometimes there are stickers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Stop Worrying About Being Perfect in the Pose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many times many of us felt were trying to hang on than emulate a cover of Yoga Journal. While that was the case for me, my fellow trainees mentioned at times trying to look as graceful as the others in their first yoga classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When focused only on your mat, the first lesson reinforces this second. My teacher stressed we are each built different. The movements we were learning would expose that. What is easy for one person can be difficult for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butterfly () is a sitting pose with palms of the feet together and heels brought toward the pelvis. It opens the hips and stretches the inner thighs. The first time she put us into that pose almost everyone’s knees were high in the air even the teacher. But my knees were on the floor. &quot;GOD DAMN YOU SCOTT, I&apos;ve been trying to get there for years&quot; she said. I felt proud then but later found that I do not bend forward at the hips at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. We Only Punish Ourselves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because cycling has a culture of suffering that as athletes we punish ourselves. This is not to say that any pose in yoga should be painful; it should not be. For example as Americans we feel like we get more value for our time in a class if we work to our max. Thus I’d fall over in poses I was nailing the week or two before. Nothing was wrong with me as a person, just with that day. When we would struggle in the warm up after attacking each other on the roads, she&apos;d tell us how to adjust the pose or take less bend in the knee. As we learned lesson two, then we came to understand this lesson. At the time I did not know we were learning to connect to ourselves and listen to how much our body could do than what our egos wanted it to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. We Limit Ourselves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ego or minds may feel like the drivers of our corporal selves. When we think of mind over body, we&apos;re not listening to create the feedback loop of bodies telling our minds what’s possible. So the third idea opened us to this fourth. Often the best part of class was to just do, and stop thinking first. We moved where she asked us to move next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing so I found I could do things I had not imagined. We&apos;d be in downward dog and the teacher would say okay jump to seated. Our heads would pop up with a look of “Huh?”. Then she would show us and cajole us to try. Some would freak out mid-movement, others would got most of it, but we all fell and had a laugh. We would try again next week.  Years later at my first primary series ashtanga class it shocked me that I had been doing jump thrus all along at a bike shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Have Fun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last point leads to this one. My first yoga teacher was unconventional. We practiced on concrete floors of a bike shop with an industrial interior design. The music she brought for class was hip hop to Red Hot Chili Peppers. She swore a lot. I mean, A LOT, as she dropped f-bombs it was not at us in anger but for us in our exasperation at doing something new. Doing so created a relaxed environment where we began to create some space in our bodies, in ourselves and for others. In the end the lesson was life is fun, so stop taking everything, even yoga, so serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yoga can be discombobulating the first few times. It gets easier with practice but your perceptions can be the greatest barrier to having a good experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>